<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-12T21:45:53+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LokSabha22</title><subtitle>A Blog by DebSoc</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nitish Kumar Interview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/nitish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nitish Kumar Interview" /><published>2022-06-12T21:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T21:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/nitish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/nitish.html"><![CDATA[<p>Nitish Kumar finally broke his silence on UCC matters in the 2nd parliamentary session by bashing BJP for trying to implement UCC in Bihar, which according to him isn’t a wise move.</p>

<p>The CM further elaborated that implementing UCC will be disastrous in Bihar as it would instigate the already polarized communities and incite riots. Moreover, he mentioned that implementing UCC will be detrimental towards protecting minorities and would impact freedom of religion.</p>

<p>In the interview, Nitish Kumar mentioned that Bihar is going through a delicate state and he wouldn’t want anything that will tip the fragile balance and lead to violence.</p>

<p>All of this brings out the discord within JDU in recent years. In April 2022, a JDU minister, Ashok Chaudhary, who is Nitish Kumar’s aide said that Bihar didn’t need UCC as the state is very peaceful. </p>

<p>The aforementioned statement was in stark contrast to the CM’s views, and upon being questioned about it, he replied that his opinion differs from those in his own party. This brings up the question - is JDU working towards bringing Bihar out of its “fragile” state, when its own MLAs live in ignorance?</p>

<p>The CM made no comments on the future of UCC in Bihar, but had previously written to the Law Commission regarding the same, in which he pressed that UCC, though useful, must be delayed in Bihar.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nitish Kumar finally broke his silence on UCC matters in the 2nd parliamentary session by bashing BJP for trying to implement UCC in Bihar, which according to him isn’t a wise move.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?" /><published>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .</p>

<p>The recently suspended spokesperson Nupur Sharma also talked about how everyone should be under one umbrella but faced strong backlash from the opposition leaders like VIJAYAN that nupur sharma herself gave a very controversial remark on prophet which is being acknowledged all over the world and Mr. Vijayan also talks about how BJP keeps naming the cities according to a “particular” religion and how there are many cases of religion bias in BJP ruling states . He supposedly concreted his claim in front of the executive board that the Uniform civil code made by the ruling party won't be that uniform ….</p>

<p>But in totally contrast to the above claims by the BJP ministers about the UCC being not biased MR. tejaswi Surya who was punished for 15 min silence in the lok sabha where he was downvoted by his own party members on a point to reply , he openly stated that how the muslims laws were totally impractical and claimed the superiority of hindu laws , he even said “Teen-Teen shadiyan karne se pehle kuch kaam kar lete hai ” while addressing Mr Owasii.</p>

<p>In the moderated caucus on the topic “if not UCC then what ”</p>

<p>Mr. nitin gadkari says that their parties main focus will be on eradicating “unfair or evil “ practices from the religious laws but was rightly opposed by shree Rahul Gandhi that the norms of “evil” are being judged by BJP. He gives example of beef ban in BJP led UTTAR PRADESH where beef was evil according to a “particular” religion so the claims of evil and not evil are totally controversial.</p>

<p>On an interesting note Mr. Jamyang Namgyal was captured sleeping in the parliament during his "own" Prime minister Narendra Modi's speech.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/07.jpg" alt="Image">]]></content><author><name>NDTV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UCC, a Tool to Pave the way for a Pro-Hindu Nation?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCC, a Tool to Pave the way for a Pro-Hindu Nation?" /><published>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC.html"><![CDATA[<p> In today’s Lok Sabha session, delegates debated over the practicality and feasibility of implementing Uniform Civil Code on Indian citizens to change personal laws. After the session, one thing is clear : “Secularism is just a word to hide the hindu nationalist sentiments of the Modi Govt” pointed out by Gaurav Gogoi.</p>

<p>In an issue like this, as clearly stated by Rahul Gandhi, there can be no real neutrality. Some communities will have to bend over in search for uniformity, which will evidently end up being the minority, with a hindu nationalist party being the majority.</p>

<p>Throughout today's session, a multitude of points were raised, both in favour and against India's lack of a UCC. One of the most important points that was raised was “Is the implementation of secularism really secular, if it’s oppressing minorities?” by none other than the president of the INC, Sonia Gandhi. She went on to explain how UCC would be a way to curb religious freedom of minorities, something that is granted to the people by the constitution. This was poorly countered by Jyotiraditya Scindia who stated that the first law reformed by Nehru was a Hindu personal law. </p>

<p>For the BJP, today’s agenda was simple. Overpower the opposition with their overwhelming majority, by backing up every weak point raised by their party. This was seen when there was unanimous voting towards the topic "If not UCC then what?", a motion raised by a BJP member, but when the time came to speak, the response from their side was underwhelming.</p>

<p>Nupur Sharma, the ex spokesperson of the BJP claimed most minority religions had aggressive laws that could only be controlled by the implementation of a UCC. This is days after she was caught making offensive comments about the Muslim Prophet. After that, can we really take what she says as constructive discussion, or is it just Islamophobia?</p>

<p>After debating over whether or not UCC could be implemented, the debate turned to alternatives for the UCC, and whether or not they would be sustainable in a country as vast and diverse as India. Points were raised by Tejasvi Surya, who loudly exclaimed that triple talaq and polygamy were sustainable, before clarifying that he was being “sarcastic”. Asaduddin Owaisi raised questions about “If you are not able to win wars on the borders of our country, why are you trying to start new wars in it”, restating the issue of communal violence. He and Tejasvi Surya had a heated debate about this point, with the former also attacking the latter’s character, to which Tejasvi raised a right to reply, and lost.</p>

<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia tried to come up with ways to implement the UCC, most of which did not hold up under scrutiny. One of the ways was to take the “best of all worlds” while picking and choosing laws, that would be ultimately decided by a separate board. But, would the board be able to represent all the people of India, and not just make laws that represent the majority?</p>

<p>Throughout the first session, BJP leaders were called out multiple times by the Chair for being disruptive and not following decorum, banging the table unnecessarily, raising abusive slogans and overall showing disrespect.</p>

<p>In the second session, Mamta Banerjee spoke about how it is the Modi Govt and “his buddies in RSS” that decide the framework of the UCC. She added that “Throughout our time in the session there has been no point made on how it will be implemented, who would be given that power to alter the laws, what laws would be considered ''wrong”? This lack of information brings us back to believe in the fact that BJP has been known to misuse the law”</p>

<p>After a lot of beating around the bush, Yogi Adityanath finally suggested forming a separate committee which would have a proportional amount of representation of all communities, to which Nitish Kumar aptly replied that it would just be like a subset of the Loksabha. Yogi added that if it were to be implemented, they would do it in a few BJP controlled states, for 3 years. This raises the question of how “uniform” the code actually is.</p>

<p>So what would the BJP actually implementing the UCC imply for minorities in India? Rahul Gandhi raised the problem of Hindus being in majority in the country and would be in the mentioned committee leading to the suppression of the minorities. </p>

<p>For instance, Ramesh Potria suggested to ban the madrasas, which are an integral part of muslim culture and its propagation. Every BJP leader went on and on about Islamic laws and how they would need to be reformed. The opposition retaliated with facts about how the Ramayana and Mahabharata are taught in CBSE schools as a part of their coursework. To this he countered by saying that it was just the “history of the nation”. So in the future, will this enforce the “hindu past” of our nation, with muslims seen as invaders?</p>

<p>These hindu nationalist propagandas of the Modi government lead to uncertainty and fear amongst the minorities.</p>

<p>Is UCC just a cover up for making the whole nation follow hindu personal laws? If UCC is implemented, will India remain a secular nation, or will it turn into a majority dominated state.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Wire</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In today’s Lok Sabha session, delegates debated over the practicality and feasibility of implementing Uniform Civil Code on Indian citizens to change personal laws. After the session, one thing is clear : “Secularism is just a word to hide the hindu nationalist sentiments of the Modi Govt” pointed out by Gaurav Gogoi.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slander and Information</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slander and Information" /><published>2022-06-12T17:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T17:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session started off in a not-so-positive manner with no valid motion by any of the MPs. Disgruntled, the speaker was forced to allow a break for them to decide.</p>

<p>After a rather weird suggestion of 44 minutes, 2 minutes per speaker by Vijayan, the motion finally decided was that of Yogi Adityanath's - “framework and implementation of UCC”. </p>

<p>The speeches began with Nitin Gadkari who cited discriminatory comments made by MIM's Owaisi and offered to “dumb down” the goals of UCC for him. He elaborated on the origin of UCC, to which the Mahua Maitri asked whether he thought Britishers were superior to Indians for trying to implement a uniform civil code.</p>

<p>Arvind Kejriwal questioned the government on its ethos with BJP's Yogi Adityanath being allegedly communal. It must be noted that the CM also proclaimed “BJP detected, opinion rejected” in the middle of the parliamentary session. He was supported by an opposition member who said that BJP believes in fixing minorities' issues without consulting the minorities themselves.</p>

<p>Further, Nitish Kumar mentioned that he was against UCC despite being a supporter of BJP. He also mentioned that UCC should be implemented uniformly in all states, since it has “uniform” in its name, rather than being implemented in only the BJP ruled states first. Amit Shah responded that implementing it in all states at once would cause communal violence, which hints towards the conclusion that the BJP thinks that the BJP states are less prone to violence.</p>

<p>Owaisi reprimanded the government for repeatedly using Goa as an example of UCC, with Goa being the only state with a uniform civil code. He elaborated that the UCC in Goa had some 2800 articles, with each one laying down different laws for different people, which defeated its purpose.</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi finally made points related to the motion by highlighting that the government must consider the common ground between religions and the personal laws of different faiths. Sadly, his points were missed as the Lok Sabha erupted in a lot of cross talk.</p>

<p>Pokhriyal made inflammatory remarks about Madrasas and said that the focus on religion brainwashed the youth and denied them the same education as others. Upon being asked about Gurukuls doing the same, he responded that Gurukuls were better at providing the necessary skills and knowledge than Madrasas, which made students in Gurukuls the ideal Indians. </p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session started off in a not-so-positive manner with no valid motion by any of the MPs. Disgruntled, the speaker was forced to allow a break for them to decide.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Template for a new post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Template for a new post" /><published>2020-01-31T10:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T10:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template.html"><![CDATA[<p>Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</p>

<p>Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.</p>

<p>What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.]]></summary></entry></feed>