<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-12T21:34:06+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LokSabha22</title><subtitle>A Blog by DebSoc</subtitle><entry><title type="html">UCC, A TOOL TO PAVE THE WAY FOR A PRO-HINDU NATION?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCC, A TOOL TO PAVE THE WAY FOR A PRO-HINDU NATION?" /><published>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/UCC.html"><![CDATA[<p> In today’s Lok Sabha session, delegates debated over the practicality and feasibility of implementing Uniform Civil Code on Indian citizens to change personal laws. After the session, one thing is clear : “Secularism is just a word to hide the hindu nationalist sentiments of the Modi Govt” pointed out by Gaurav Gogoi.</p>

<p>In an issue like this, as clearly stated by Rahul Gandhi, there can be no real neutrality. Some communities will have to bend over in search for uniformity, which will evidently end up being the minority, with a hindu nationalist party being the majority.</p>

<p>Throughout today's session, a multitude of points were raised, both in favour and against India's lack of a UCC. One of the most important points that was raised was “Is the implementation of secularism really secular, if it’s oppressing minorities?” by none other than the president of the INC, Sonia Gandhi. She went on to explain how UCC would be a way to curb religious freedom of minorities, something that is granted to the people by the constitution. This was poorly countered by Jyotiraditya Scindia who stated that the first law reformed by Nehru was a Hindu personal law. </p>

<p>For the BJP, today’s agenda was simple. Overpower the opposition with their overwhelming majority, by backing up every weak point raised by their party. This was seen when there was unanimous voting towards the topic "If not UCC then what?", a motion raised by a BJP member, but when the time came to speak, the response from their side was underwhelming.</p>

<p>Nupur Sharma, the ex spokesperson of the BJP claimed most minority religions had aggressive laws that could only be controlled by the implementation of a UCC. This is days after she was caught making offensive comments about the Muslim Prophet. After that, can we really take what she says as constructive discussion, or is it just Islamophobia?</p>

<p>After debating over whether or not UCC could be implemented, the debate turned to alternatives for the UCC, and whether or not they would be sustainable in a country as vast and diverse as India. Points were raised by Tejasvi Surya, who loudly exclaimed that triple talaq and polygamy were sustainable, before clarifying that he was being “sarcastic”. Asaduddin Owaisi raised questions about “If you are not able to win wars on the borders of our country, why are you trying to start new wars in it”, restating the issue of communal violence. He and Tejasvi Surya had a heated debate about this point, with the former also attacking the latter’s character, to which Tejasvi raised a right to reply, and lost.</p>

<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia tried to come up with ways to implement the UCC, most of which did not hold up under scrutiny. One of the ways was to take the “best of all worlds” while picking and choosing laws, that would be ultimately decided by a separate board. But, would the board be able to represent all the people of India, and not just make laws that represent the majority?</p>

<p>Throughout the first session, BJP leaders were called out multiple times by the Chair for being disruptive and not following decorum, banging the table unnecessarily, raising abusive slogans and overall showing disrespect.</p>

<p>In the second session, Mamta Banerjee spoke about how it is the Modi Govt and “his buddies in RSS” that decide the framework of the UCC. She added that “Throughout our time in the session there has been no point made on how it will be implemented, who would be given that power to alter the laws, what laws would be considered ''wrong”? This lack of information brings us back to believe in the fact that BJP has been known to misuse the law”</p>

<p>After a lot of beating around the bush, Yogi Adityanath finally suggested forming a separate committee which would have a proportional amount of representation of all communities, to which Nitish Kumar aptly replied that it would just be like a subset of the Loksabha. Yogi added that if it were to be implemented, they would do it in a few BJP controlled states, for 3 years. This raises the question of how “uniform” the code actually is.</p>

<p>So what would the BJP actually implementing the UCC imply for minorities in India? Rahul Gandhi raised the problem of Hindus being in majority in the country and would be in the mentioned committee leading to the suppression of the minorities. </p>

<p>For instance, Ramesh Potria suggested to ban the madrasas, which are an integral part of muslim culture and its propagation. Every BJP leader went on and on about Islamic laws and how they would need to be reformed. The opposition retaliated with facts about how the Ramayana and Mahabharata are taught in CBSE schools as a part of their coursework. To this he countered by saying that it was just the “history of the nation”. So in the future, will this enforce the “hindu past” of our nation, with muslims seen as invaders?</p>

<p>These hindu nationalist propagandas of the Modi government lead to uncertainty and fear amongst the minorities.</p>

<p>Is UCC just a cover up for making the whole nation follow hindu personal laws? If UCC is implemented, will India remain a secular nation, or will it turn into a majority dominated state.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Wire</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In today’s Lok Sabha session, delegates debated over the practicality and feasibility of implementing Uniform Civil Code on Indian citizens to change personal laws. After the session, one thing is clear : “Secularism is just a word to hide the hindu nationalist sentiments of the Modi Govt” pointed out by Gaurav Gogoi.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slander and Information</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slander and Information" /><published>2022-06-12T17:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T17:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/slander.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session started off in a not-so-positive manner with no valid motion by any of the MPs. Disgruntled, the speaker was forced to allow a break for them to decide.</p>

<p>After a rather weird suggestion of 44 minutes, 2 minutes per speaker by Vijayan, the motion finally decided was that of Yogi Adityanath's - “framework and implementation of UCC”. </p>

<p>The speeches began with Nitin Gadkari who cited discriminatory comments made by MIM's Owaisi and offered to “dumb down” the goals of UCC for him. He elaborated on the origin of UCC, to which the Mahua Maitri asked whether he thought Britishers were superior to Indians for trying to implement a uniform civil code.</p>

<p>Arvind Kejriwal questioned the government on its ethos with BJP's Yogi Adityanath being allegedly communal. It must be noted that the CM also proclaimed “BJP detected, opinion rejected” in the middle of the parliamentary session. He was supported by an opposition member who said that BJP believes in fixing minorities' issues without consulting the minorities themselves.</p>

<p>Further, Nitish Kumar mentioned that he was against UCC despite being a supporter of BJP. He also mentioned that UCC should be implemented uniformly in all states, since it has “uniform” in its name, rather than being implemented in only the BJP ruled states first. Amit Shah responded that implementing it in all states at once would cause communal violence, which hints towards the conclusion that the BJP thinks that the BJP states are less prone to violence.</p>

<p>Owaisi reprimanded the government for repeatedly using Goa as an example of UCC, with Goa being the only state with a uniform civil code. He elaborated that the UCC in Goa had some 2800 articles, with each one laying down different laws for different people, which defeated its purpose.</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi finally made points related to the motion by highlighting that the government must consider the common ground between religions and the personal laws of different faiths. Sadly, his points were missed as the Lok Sabha erupted in a lot of cross talk.</p>

<p>Pokhriyal made inflammatory remarks about Madrasas and said that the focus on religion brainwashed the youth and denied them the same education as others. Upon being asked about Gurukuls doing the same, he responded that Gurukuls were better at providing the necessary skills and knowledge than Madrasas, which made students in Gurukuls the ideal Indians. </p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session started off in a not-so-positive manner with no valid motion by any of the MPs. Disgruntled, the speaker was forced to allow a break for them to decide.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Template for a new post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Template for a new post" /><published>2020-01-31T10:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T10:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/template.html"><![CDATA[<p>Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</p>

<p>Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.</p>

<p>What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.]]></summary></entry></feed>