<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-15T13:29:05+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LokSabha22</title><subtitle>A Blog by DebSoc</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Exclusive Hint at Badruddin Ajmal’s Lok Sabha Bill</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exclusive Hint at Badruddin Ajmal’s Lok Sabha Bill" /><published>2022-06-14T21:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T21:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal.html"><![CDATA[<p>Badruddin Ajmal provided The Hindu with an exclusive peek at the bill he proposes to publish in the Lok Sabha -</p>

The scheme we need to follow to solve the pertinent question:

<ol>
    <li>Draft a UCC.</li>
    <li>Decide cases of personal law in the following manner:
        <ol>
            <li>Ask each of the parties what law system they would like to follow</li>
            <li>If there is a unanimous consensus on a particular law system, use it. If not, use the UCC.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
</ol>

This system will preserve the freedom of religion as well as uphold the
fundamental rights of everyone, including women and minorities.

Example illustrating point ii)

Suppose there is a personal law case pertaining to marriage. Then each of the
parties in the case must choose between

<ol>
    <li> The Hindu Marriage Act, 1955 </li>
    <li> The Indian Christian Marriage Act, 1872 </li>
    <li> The Parsi Marriage and Divorce Act of 1936 </li>
    <li> Muslim Marriage Act </li>
    <li> Any other religious laws </li>
    <li> The Uniform Civil Code, 2022 </li>
</ol>

<p>If ALL the parties are in agreement on one of these options, then the agreed upon law should be the law used to decide the case.</p>

<p>Else The Uniform Civil Code, 2022 shall be used.</p>

<p>The MP proposes drafting a UCC, then debating over each and every law in personal laws with representation from all political parties, and if a unanimous decision is not achieved, a suitable clause from the UCC draft shall be implemented across India.</p>

<p>However, the proposed bill neither specifies the contents of the UCC, nor does it hint upon the members that will be a part of the drafting committee.</p>

<p>Moreover, the cause of accommodating each and every minority in India, including women, hasn’t been discussed in the draft we received.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Badruddin Ajmal provided The Hindu with an exclusive peek at the bill he proposes to publish in the Lok Sabha -]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drama in Moderated Caucus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drama in Moderated Caucus" /><published>2022-06-14T20:00:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T20:00:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus.html"><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi commenced the speeches with the government’s plan to implement UCC with an introduction to the committee structure, which will have a proportional representation from Lok Sabha MPs and equal representation from all minorities and women rights advocates. UCC will first be implemented in BJP ruled states such as Uttar Pradesh, and will be enforced all over India in three years. Upon being asked about the proportion of Lok Sabha members in the committee by Vijayan, Modi promptly replied that he didn’t need to clarify and that the plan should be looked up.<p>

<p>Nupur Sharma said that the proportional representation will be that of political parties and contradicted the PM by saying that the “experiment” in specific states will last for three years. She also said that implementing in some states first will prevent uprising.<p>

<p>Vijayan pointed out that the NDA just recently started talking about the implementation of UCC, and that it was ironic that the same people who want UCC don’t have a single clue about how to implement it. He elaborated that the CPI(M) initially supported UCC but no longer does as the predominant supporter of the same, i.e. BJP is involved in the oppression of minorities. He suggested changing the personal laws instead which would achieve the same goals as the UCC as explained by the BJP. Nupur Sharma replied that the agenda of implementing UCC was to bring everyone under a common law, and Modi said that implementing UCC in BJP ruled states will be successful as time would be spent actually seeing the effects of the law rather than bickering with state governments such as that of Mamata Banerjee.<p>

<p>Uddhav Thakeray pressed that UCC was required for national unity, and that it will remove the pressure and influence of foreign entities on personal law boards. Gogoi continues by bashing BJP by saying that implementing in BJP ruled states won’t prevent riots by pointing towards the clashes and protests caused by Nupur Sharma’s remarks last week. Gogoi bashed BJP by announcing that the anti-Muslim and that the only reason that they were against polygamous marriage was that it was allows allowed to Sharia law. He said that BJP is in the business of passing bills without consulting any of the relevant stakeholders first. Modi replied that he doesn’t care about any religious scriptures; all that matters is that everyone enjoys basic human rights. It must be noted that Irani said that personal laws resembled the divide and conquer method used by the British.<p>

<p>“Women’s rights are subjective, “said Farooq Abdullah. He mentioned that human rights are subject to cultural interpretation, and that Kashmiris still protest against the removal of article 370. Tharoor added that the government plans on sitting and watching as the introduction of UCC in select states will lead to the same turmoil the nation experienced during the 2002 Gujarat riots. Shashi Tharoor continued by saying that the government cannot be trusted to uphold the dignity and culture of minorities as BJP ruled states have passed laws against religious conversion, which was responded to by stating that the laws were anti-forceful conversion.<p>

<p>Manohar Lal Khattar passes an inflammatory comment when he said that some personal laws didn’t respect females, and refused to list down the referred personal laws. He also announced that the entire parliament will get to decide on members of the UCC committee.<p>

<p>MK Stalin was certainly not taking the matter seriously as he was laughing and swaying while giving his speech. He said that the DMK will support UCC as long as it’s implemented in the same way as Ajmal intended. He added that India should “de-moss” and copy UK’s or USSR’s UCC implementations as the BJP wasn’t capable.<p>

<p>Naqvi reprimanded the opposition for repeatedly taking things out of context. He mentioned that intellect isn’t affected by religion, and that changing personal laws didn’t achieve the same thing as UCC as law making isn’t about accommodating some people more and some less; everyone must be equal. Rahul Gandhi passed a sarcastic remark by saying that “Religious communities will definitely be respectful of other religions.”. In his reply, Naqvi reminded the opposition that protests don’t mean that the action was wrong - it can also mean that some people misinterpreted the action.<p>

<p>Swami expressed his opinion that Stalin was very concerned about the contents of the UCC, and Kejriwal said that BJP was interested in meddling with personal laws. BJP replied to the CM by saying that the aspiration for UCC is present under Article 44 of the constitution, and that changes such as implementing the Hindu Succession law wasn’t taken well by people initially but its results are evident. Kejriwal further added that the government cited article 44 a lot, but didn’t pay heed to Article 35 which said that UCC should only be implemented when there was a general agreement across the nation. The opposition pressed that BJP engages in polarizing Indians which was clearly evident with BJP’s share in Hindu votes rising exponentially through the years.<p>

<p>The moderated caucus that had begun the previous session ended at 4PM. It was observed that the speaker was biased in not letting certain vocal MPs reply to the other blocks.<p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi commenced the speeches with the government’s plan to implement UCC with an introduction to the committee structure, which will have a proportional representation from Lok Sabha MPs and equal representation from all minorities and women rights advocates. UCC will first be implemented in BJP ruled states such as Uttar Pradesh, and will be enforced all over India in three years. Upon being asked about the proportion of Lok Sabha members in the committee by Vijayan, Modi promptly replied that he didn’t need to clarify and that the plan should be looked up.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The opposition says some things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The opposition says some things" /><published>2022-06-14T19:19:19+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T19:19:19+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things.html"><![CDATA[<p>The second day of the Lok Sabha picks up from where the first one ended. Some more barbs regarding implementation of UCC are traded, and a point of contention is about the initial implementation of UCC being in Gujarat and Uttar Pradesh, communally diverse states which are governed by the BJP. The opposition questions why a phased rollout, and why in states governed by the BJP. The central government’s response points out that a phased rollout helps to observe how well it works, and the practical difficulties faced can be fixed in the subsequently chosen states. The reason for choosing those states is that the central government would prefer working with co-operative state governments, and not those who would seek to complain and create hurdles at every turn and delay the process at every turn, an example being the TMC government in West Bengal.<p>

<p>Another ‘problem’ brought up was that Uttar Pradesh had the lowest Human Development Index (HDI) in India, which is objectively untrue and was fact-checked by UP CM Yogi Adityanath. Modiji closed by asking the pertinent question of where his concerns ought to lie, in the safety and happiness of women or in what Sharia law or the Holy Bible say?<p>

<p>The assembly then broke for an unmoderated caucus. Amazingly, AIUDF chief Badruddin Ajmal, who is regularly listed among <a href="https://themuslim500.com/profiles/badruddin-ajmal-qasmi/">"The 500 Most Influential Muslims" of the world</a>, was heard saying ‘India is not a nice country, there are much nicer countries,’ with Hyderabad MP Asaduddin Owaisi repeatedly asking him to ‘shut up, the press is right here.’<p>

<p>After the unmoderated caucus, there were some crisis updates, which caused quite a stir. Foremost among them was the fact that RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat had stated that he was excited to join the special committee of the UCC. The opposition made quite a meal of this statement even after it was clarified that he was simply one of those considered for it, and that there would be equal representation for all.<p>

<p>Mamata Bannerjee and Arvind Kejriwal threatened to go to the Supreme Court even though the matter was still under discussion in the House. Kejriwal also made the distractionary demand of statehood for Delhi. The BJP revealed that it had modified its original plan to now implement UCC first in West Bengal, Kerala, Kashmir, and Uttar Pradesh after consultation with the opposition, indicating that they are and have been open to constructive criticism.<p>

<p>One of the most controversial speeches of the day came towards the end and was made by TMC MP Mahua Moitra, who asked, “Do you think Indians have the brains to follow  UCC laws? India is going to lawless and weak cowards… Indians don’t have listening skills and have a short attention span.” One wonders why the representative felt the need to be so provocative in her speech, and what she intended to achieve.<p>

<p>The day closed with an open press conference. Turn to Page 2 for  our coverage.<p>]]></content><author><name>Zee News</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second day of the Lok Sabha picks up from where the first one ended. Some more barbs regarding implementation of UCC are traded, and a point of contention is about the initial implementation of UCC being in Gujarat and Uttar Pradesh, communally diverse states which are governed by the BJP. The opposition questions why a phased rollout, and why in states governed by the BJP. The central government’s response points out that a phased rollout helps to observe how well it works, and the practical difficulties faced can be fixed in the subsequently chosen states. The reason for choosing those states is that the central government would prefer working with co-operative state governments, and not those who would seek to complain and create hurdles at every turn and delay the process at every turn, an example being the TMC government in West Bengal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BJP marches on with UCC plans, Modi supports Nupur Sharma, other party members outraged</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BJP marches on with UCC plans, Modi supports Nupur Sharma, other party members outraged" /><published>2022-06-14T17:40:28+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T17:40:28+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc.html"><![CDATA[<p>In stark contrast to yesterday today’s session saw a plethora of developments during the committee’s discussion on UCC.<p>

<p>Two prominent CMs, Jagan Reddy of Telangana and MK Stalin of Tamil Nadu finally showed up to the committee, wanting to make an impact on the proceedings (spoiler alert – they didn’t)<p>

<p>The session began with the committee continuing the discussion which took place yesterday: on the implementation of the UCC. However, unlike yesterday, the pro-UCC bloc actually had a proper plan this time. The Prime Minister and other pro-UCC bloc members talked about creating a committee with proportionate representation from the Lok Sabha, and equal representation from all religions and minorities on top of that. The BJP would not comment, however, on the proportions of the representation.<p>

<p>A 3-year trial period was also planned for implementation of UCC in BJP-ruled states, after which it would be implemented in other states (based on the success of the trial period). <p>

<p>The anti-UCC bloc pointed out that the proposed committee representation would still end up being biased towards Hindus, with Akhilesh Yadav in particular calling out how “minorities will be under-represented”. The decision of only trialling the system in BJP-ruled states was also heavily criticized.<p>

<p>It seemed that MK Stalin was blissfully unaware of the magnitude of the issue at hand, as he was seen giggling and laughing for little reason throughout the session. Even during his speech, he chose to be in support of the UCC if “Badruddin Ajmal’s interpretation is followed”. Remember, this was the leader who previously claimed that UCC was “an attempt to divert attention by the Union government”. When called out on this deviation by the other MPs, his only defence was that his party was a “flexible party which wants to listen to the needs of the people”. Though, it seems unclear why Stalin is suddenly pandering to Hindus.<p>

<p>Some MPs such as Abbas Naqvi were still innocent enough to believe in ideal-world scenarios. He claimed that “respected individuals from one community will not cause harm to other communities”, and that “intellect doe not have a religion”. When issues of instigated communal riots were brought up, Naqvi was unable to provide a response, apart from an attempt at deflecting the blame back at Rahul by noting how there were riots in his constituency as well. It was unclear how this was related to Rahul’s question and how Naqvi thought it would strengthen his point.<p>

<p>Farooq Abdullah’s history of eye-raising comments continued as he called women’s rights a “subjective matter”. When pressed on this point, he claimed that BJP “does not have the right to decide what women’s rights are”.<p>

<p>The committee then broke for a small informal session where both blocs tried to strengthen their battle plan. But while this was happening, it was observed that Badruddin Ajmal was going around to every person with “something” in his hand and asking for their opinion and support on the matter. Upon a minor investigation, it was revealed that Ajmal had already created a bill toward the implementation of the UCC, and was trying to get support for it. He would eventually announce it in public later on, and sure enough, he also ended up changing blocs after the break.<p>

<p>However, that wasn’t remotely the biggest development during the break. BJP were so confident in their numeric advantage, that they released a statement noting their confidence on UCC being implemented in the next 3 years. The proposed committee would consist of people whom the Lok Sabha deemed “relevant stakeholders”. BJP also drastically altered the pilot states for the trial, choosing to test the UCC in Kerala, West Bengal, Kashmir and Uttar Pradesh. And as if that was not enough, the RSS President publicly expressed his “excitement” to join the UCC draft committee.<p>

<p>Needless to say, the anti-UCC bloc was completely outraged. Their view was that the states selected were not “random”, and was a deliberate ploy to suppress the people in these states. Kerala’s CM Pinarayi Vijayan strongly believed that if anything went wrong during the process, his people would be labelled anti-nationalists. Multiple members insinuated that the BJP would even declare an Emergency.<p>

<p>BJP’s response? They were merely doing what the house told them to do – make the list of trial states as diverse as possible. PM Modi retorted by pointing out the hypocrisy of the complaining anti-UCC bloc by noting that “these were the same people who complained when BJP-ruled states were picked”. But they were unable to provide other suitable responses for this decision.<p>

<p>The developments also resulted in multiple MPs “flexibly” changing their stance on the matter. MPs like Farooq Abdullah now were “begging” the BJP to trial the UCC only in BJP-ruled states, something which they had vehemently opposed prior to the recent developments. <p>

<p>Another issue of major contention was the supposed inclusion of the RSS President in the UCC draft committee. Many members of the house brought up his colourful history – Owaisi mentioned him “calling for open murder of Muslims” – and were incensed that a right-wing Hindu nationalist was given a spot in committee. Owaisi wondered if the RSS President got a spot in the committee, why did he – a member of AIMPLB – not get a spot on the committee yet?<p>

<p>The BJP MPs seemed to provide different responses for these questions. Nirmala Sitharaman was of the opinion that the RSS president has the sympathy of a lot of Hindu people in the country, making him a relevant stakeholder – basically confirming his inclusion into the committee. But Nupur Sharma and Narendra Modi said otherwise, arguing that the RSS President was only under consideration and was talked to regarding the committee. They attempted to deflect the issue by mentioning that they had no control over what the RSS President says in public. It was clear that there were some cracks in the BJP’s story.<p>

<p>Later on, a press conference took place where the MPs were grilled by reporters from the various press bodies. Throughout the course of this conference, multiple leaders suffered from “severe amnesia”, and those who didn’t, made several accusations of “fake news”.<p>

<p>It was during this press conference when PM Modi dropped the biggest bombshell of the night – he openly voiced his support for Nupur Sharma. His view was that her comments were a result of her freedom of speech, which should be respected. Wonder how he would have reacted if the deity being defamed was a Hindu one: would he still be rambling about “freedom of speech”?<p>]]></content><author><name>Times of India</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In stark contrast to yesterday today’s session saw a plethora of developments during the committee’s discussion on UCC.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BJP says UCC to be implemented in states of Kerala, West Bengal. Is it just a coincidence?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BJP says UCC to be implemented in states of Kerala, West Bengal. Is it just a coincidence?" /><published>2022-06-14T16:00:44+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T16:00:44+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session today started with the the parliament trying to find  proper implementation methods of UCC to which senior BJP ministers like Mr. modi and Ms Nupur Sharma suggested to make a prototype of the UCC rules by making a committee having “proportionate” representation political party members and religious members , this “ proportionate “ was questioned by the congress leader and raised many speculation of how the BJP is trying to ‘HINDUFY’ the country.<p>

<p>BJP leaders also suggested the implementation should be trial for 3 years in the states of kerala ,west bengal .This suggestion faced strong backlash from the opposition leaders .Mr. Owaisi rightly opposed it with the argument  that BJP’s selection of states is not “random” owaisi points out how they have selected the states not ruled by BJP so that riots which follow (which are inevitable ) will be blamed on the state , on this note PM modi even commented that if the riots are violent they won't hesitate to put an emergency which essentially puts the center in charge<p>

<p>Press conference followed in the later part of the day where NDTV reporters had the chance to interview the all talented and sensible BJP minister Mr. Tejaswi Surya . when asked about how can the people of the nation trust him and the BJP while making the rules for UCC after openly giving  the remarks about how muslim religioun is so impractical and making fun of many sharia laws , he stubornly replied to this question that since the people have voted him they have to trust him even if he gives nasty remarks on muslim laws.<p>

<p>And when asked about his views on an incident in uttar pradesh he replied with i don't care about uttar pradesh ,i am from bangalore , as if the UCC (if implemented )will be implemented only in his constituencies and not in the entire nation.<p>

<p>In the press conference the prime minister of the nation Mr. Narendra Damodar Modi  didn’t had answers to most questions asked by the press (maybe he is out of practice in attending press conferences ) but he was very confident in speaking in support of Ms Nupur “controversy” Sharma about the nasty remarks she gave on prophet mohammed , He defended Ms Sharma calling her remarks as freedom of speech (offensive speech never existed ) . Modi ji did this after Nupur Sharma had openly accepted that her suspension from the party was correct .<p>

<p>This shows how the BJP represents itself as a secular party and then like a snake shed its skin and show its true color.<p>

<p>Now the question is Will the parliament come to a conclusion on the final day , will the all efficient speakers of the BJP be able to brainwash the parliament with their supposedly “right” ideas or will the UCC remain a myth as it always has been …<p>]]></content><author><name>NDTV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session today started with the the parliament trying to find proper implementation methods of UCC to which senior BJP ministers like Mr. modi and Ms Nupur Sharma suggested to make a prototype of the UCC rules by making a committee having “proportionate” representation political party members and religious members , this “ proportionate “ was questioned by the congress leader and raised many speculation of how the BJP is trying to ‘HINDUFY’ the country.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jyotiraditya Scindi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jyotiraditya Scindi" /><published>2022-06-14T15:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T15:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia, the Congress member who switched BJP in 2020, was interviewed by The Hindu in the first session of the Parliament today.</p>

<p><i>The interview commenced only after the Rajya Sabha MP glanced through the web to check whether The Hindu’s political alliance lied with the NDA.</i> <b>The Hindu would like to press that we don’t affiliate ourselves with any political entity, Indian or otherwise, and are completely unbiased in our views.</b><p>

<p>In your experience, out of BJP and Congress, which party do you think respects the secular nature of the country?<p>

<p>Scindia replied that he thought BJP was more accommodating of minorities’ opinions. He didn’t comment on the revolts in response to CAA, and other such NDA implemented laws.<p>

<p>Are you aware of some other countries that have implemented UCC? The MP replied that he did. Are you aware of the fact that Saudi Arabia has a uniform civil code? The MP wasn’t. <p>

<p>Countries such as Saudi Arabia, Turkey, Pakistan and so on, have a uniform code for everyone, but in contrast to the aspirations of the Indian constitution, it has been implemented according to Sharia law.<p>

<p>With reference to the last question, how can the nation trust BJP, a Hindutva party, to implement the UCC while considering the views of everyone? <p>

<p>The MP reiterated the government’s plans to have equal representation from all communities and proportional representation from the parliamentary members. Scindia added that the one of the main goals of UCC was to ensure equal rights for all women in the country and uphold the dignity of females. <p>

<p>What would you like to comment on Ramesh Pokhriyal saying that education in gurukuls produced the ideal Indians and education in madrasas brainwashed the youth?<p>

<p>The MP didn’t comment and provided the excuse of not being present in the parliament house when the inflammatory comment was made.<p>

<p>In your speech in the first session, you mentioned that India should follow the Belgium model. Could you elaborate on that?<p>

<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia mentioned the key characteristics of the Belgian problem - different language speaking majorities and special community governments that had the power to handle issues related, and address grievances, related to their own communities. <p>

<p>In Belgium, the communal governments have power over educational, cultural, and language related issues. Bar marriage related issues, isn’t this the same as personal laws in India? <p>

<p>The MP evaded the question and reiterated the point of a UCC. <p>

<p>In 2014, you mentioned that BJP polarizes the Indian community and damages the secular nature of our country. What has changed between then and 2022?<p>

<p>Scindia mentioned that opinions and facts change with time.<p>

<p>How do you feel about the fact that you rub shoulders with the same people who were present in the BJP when you made the previous comment?<p>

<p>The MP replied that opinions and people are allowed to change.<p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jyotiraditya Scindia, the Congress member who switched BJP in 2020, was interviewed by The Hindu in the first session of the Parliament today.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Owaisi Says, “UCC Takes Away Rights From Women”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Owaisi Says, “UCC Takes Away Rights From Women”" /><published>2022-06-12T22:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T22:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Lok Sabha Assembly’s first day marked a rather enthusiastic session. While it was an enthusiastic session with participation from most of the Members of the Parliament voicing their concerns regarding the Uniform Civil Code, it was apparent that the opposition was not able to provide convincing alternatives to UCC if not UCC, and continued vouching for the age-old discriminatory laws.</p>

<p>The session started with the Motion proposed by the Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh, a UCC advocate, “framework and implementation of UCC”.</p>

<p>Towards the beginning of the session, Union Minister Mukhtar Abbas Naqvi backed up his previous statements by portraying strong approval towards implementing the Uniform Civil Code for all the citizens of India. He said, “India is a nation of peace and acceptance. people are arrogant to assume personal laws are superior.” He claimed that the “heavenly laws” made about 2000 years ago were discriminatory towards women and the less fortunate people of the society and UCC would ensure they are given rights.</p>

<p>On a rather interesting note, Asaduddin Owaisi explicitly said that the UCC would take away rights from women. He quoted that, “Hindu women have certain privileges that the UCC would in fact withdraw”. The panel of BJP MPs objected to this completely false statement. Owaisi seemed to have incorrectly learned and interpreted the UCC, as Anurag Thakur backed up, “UCC takes into consideration the current personal laws and does not take them away.“</p>

<p>Owaisi was further questioned by the right-leaning MPs when he mentioned, “Polygamy among Hindus was in fact more than the polygamy found in Muslims”. This statement not only baffled the panel of members of the parliament, but left the audience, press, and the speaker perplexed. Upon being questioned about his sources, he mentioned and we quote “1954 census reported this.” These laughable comments were visibly cross-examined by the audience as it left them confused.</p>

<p>MP Manoj Tiwari, remarkably convinced his point that the opposition has based their entire problems on the implementations of UCC and has not rather given a thought about the overall picture and how beneficial it could be. He conveyed his message by using quite an interesting “pizza” analogy. He reinstated that we are all Indian citizens above all and that existence of personal identity will not be harmed, which the opposition seemed to have forgotten.</p>

<p>Admittedly going against his own party’s stated position Tharoor, in fact, backed the idea proposed by BJP. He said, “this law has the capability of giving women and the people of the LGBTQ community rights.” He also received support and applause from the ruling party for stating, “One nation, One Law”.</p>

<p>During the second motion, “If not UCC, then what?” proposed by Scindia, it became apparent that the opposition had no clear idea about what they had in mind if not UCC. According to spokesperson Manoj Tiwari, “opposition’s policy is completely redundant and they should just go along with UCC. Implementation of UCC is also a matter of debate. Stating and wording UCC in a different way is not suggesting an alternative.”</p>

<p>Today’s session, although was only the first of the many to come, made the picture very clear. The ruling party had a sharp vision of the UCC and its framework, however, the opposition, confused, could not give good enough alternatives to UCC, nor could completely criticise UCC.</p>]]></content><author><name>Republic TV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Lok Sabha Assembly’s first day marked a rather enthusiastic session. While it was an enthusiastic session with participation from most of the Members of the Parliament voicing their concerns regarding the Uniform Civil Code, it was apparent that the opposition was not able to provide convincing alternatives to UCC if not UCC, and continued vouching for the age-old discriminatory laws.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?" /><published>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .</p>

<p>The recently suspended spokesperson Nupur Sharma also talked about how everyone should be under one umbrella but faced strong backlash from the opposition leaders like VIJAYAN that nupur sharma herself gave a very controversial remark on prophet which is being acknowledged all over the world and Mr. Vijayan also talks about how BJP keeps naming the cities according to a “particular” religion and how there are many cases of religion bias in BJP ruling states . He supposedly concreted his claim in front of the executive board that the Uniform civil code made by the ruling party won't be that uniform ….</p>

<p>But in totally contrast to the above claims by the BJP ministers about the UCC being not biased MR. tejaswi Surya who was punished for 15 min silence in the lok sabha where he was downvoted by his own party members on a point to reply , he openly stated that how the muslims laws were totally impractical and claimed the superiority of hindu laws , he even said “Teen-Teen shadiyan karne se pehle kuch kaam kar lete hai ” while addressing Mr Owasii.</p>

<p>In the moderated caucus on the topic “if not UCC then what ”</p>

<p>Mr. nitin gadkari says that their parties main focus will be on eradicating “unfair or evil “ practices from the religious laws but was rightly opposed by shree Rahul Gandhi that the norms of “evil” are being judged by BJP. He gives example of beef ban in BJP led UTTAR PRADESH where beef was evil according to a “particular” religion so the claims of evil and not evil are totally controversial.</p>

<p>On an interesting note Mr. Jamyang Namgyal was captured sleeping in the parliament during his "own" Prime minister Narendra Modi's speech.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/07.jpeg" alt="Image">]]></content><author><name>NDTV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TOI Interviews Nitin Gadkari</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/Gadkari.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TOI Interviews Nitin Gadkari" /><published>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T19:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/Gadkari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/Gadkari.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Times of India had the opportunity to interview Shri Nitin Gadkari towards the end of the second session of the Lok Sabha. The interview was a strained one, as there were multiple instances where Gadkari forgot/feigned ignorance about some of the comments he made during the session (and also instances where he claimed his quote was misinterpreted): but he’s a pretty old guy, so we can probably forgive him for that.</p>

<p>When questioned about his comment on “wanting the members of the Lok Sabha to be the jurists responsible for the UCC”, Gadkari went off on a tangent about how modern India was on verge of a breakthrough which he believed the UCC could provide. He also claimed that there was a massive amount of “extraction” on small religious communities, and he only wished to protect human rights and not encroach them.</p>

<p>But there were doubts raised regarding the possibility of bias, as Gadkari had made some ignorant comments in the media – notably, he had called the hijab row “a small matter”. When asked about this, he initially mentioned not remembering his words, and then arguing that his words were “misinterpreted”. He then mentioned how he “trusts the opposition more than himself to correct him” (whatever that means)</p>

<p>Gadkari also vehemently argued against the fact that determining and removing “unfair and evil” practices was a subjective and controversial issue, as he felt that the laws which needed to be removed were mostly “black and white”. </p>

<p>However, this was refuted when the issue of the beef and hijab bans were brought up. Gadkari claimed that the hijab ban was only introduced as there was a “large percentage” of Muslim women who did not wish to cover their face and felt oppressed by this act (which is incorrect, as 89% of Muslim women voluntarily wear hijabs). He also did not wish to comment on the beef ban.</p>

<p>Later, Gadkari was also asked about his comments about how “Bihar would not get priority on UCC implementation as it is not a BJP-ruled state”. Gadkari’s response was how he merely wished to correct Nitish Kumar’s logical fallacy on the matter. He also claimed that it was a logical observation to note that there was a higher chance of UCC being passed in BJP-ruled states.</p>

<p>Gadkari was the first MP to bring up a state-wise implementation of UCC. But weirdly enough, he denied this as he thought Amit Shah brought it up earlier (another instance of foggy memory). He only “relented” when confronted with proof about the timings of the statements.</p>

<p>When questioned about how a state-wise implementation of UCC would contradict the fact that it was meant to be a “uniform” code, Gadkari was unable to provide a proper response, merely stating that the laws would be the same for the states.</p>]]></content><author><name>Times of India</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Times of India had the opportunity to interview Shri Nitin Gadkari towards the end of the second session of the Lok Sabha. The interview was a strained one, as there were multiple instances where Gadkari forgot/feigned ignorance about some of the comments he made during the session (and also instances where he claimed his quote was misinterpreted): but he’s a pretty old guy, so we can probably forgive him for that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who Doesn’t Want a Pizza ? A Weirdough</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/pizza.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who Doesn’t Want a Pizza ? A Weirdough" /><published>2022-06-12T16:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T16:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/pizza</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/pizza.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first day began with a General Speakers’ List (GSL) with 20 speakers, lasting 30 minutes. The topic of discussion was the Uniform Civil Code(UCC). The first couple of hours consisted of banal back-and-forth between the opposition and the government, with all representatives making the same points – the opposition stating, “you can’t impose your rules on other communities,” and the government enlightening them: “ Many of the personal laws are prejudiced against women in general. Hence, we must have a uniform code to ensure parity for all.”</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/09.jpg" alt="Image">

<p>The opposition mentioned that the implementation of UCC in Goa(a BJP-ruled state) was imperfect and “not actually uniform”, but Minister of Finance Sitharaman sets them straight by womansplaining to them that those laws were brought about by the Portuguese, and honestly it’s unreasonable to blame the current government for them.</p>

<p>Nitin Gadkari asked the pertinent question of human rights taking precedence over all other rights and choice. He said that you can still practise your own religion, but the evil laws should be rid of. This is true even of Hinduism, as in the case of Sati. However, Akhilesh Yadav took offence to Gadkari’s unapologetic usage of the word ‘evil’, raised a right to reply… AND LOST. like a bich. So he had to shut up for 15 minutes</p>

<p>Next up, Manoj Tiwari made an interesting analogy about a son not wanting pizza from Domino’s when asked if he wanted to order online(he compared this with the opposition discussing the implementation of UCC when they hadn’t even decided if UCC would be implemented), and Vijayan responded by saying they don’t want pizza at all. (I know, right? What a weirdo. Whatever. More pizza for the rest of us) The overarching theme seemed to be that the opposition wanted a UCC, but were not in favour of the ruling party formulating it, as their laws were apparently “hInDu-BiAsEd”.</p>

<p>Amidst all this, Yogiji raised his hand to speak, but the rapporteur ignored him >:( that’s strike one.</p>

<p>Shashi Tharoor started talking again, and disrespected Tejaswi Surya. What he didn’t realise was that he had forgotten his haute “accent”. Thanks to the rapporteur for pointing that out. You’re off the hook. For now. We break for an hour.</p>

<p>The topic for the second session is “If not UCC, then what?”</p>

<p>We’re supposed to hear the alternatives the opposition has to a UCC. (Spoiler: none of them are any good)</p>

<p>Rahul Gandhi pipes up, and stumbles through his speech. Elmayo noob. His own associates disturb his speech, showing a lack of unity and coordination in Congress and the opposition as a whole. He takes the metaphor in a completely new (and nonsensical) direction by bringing up pineapple on pizza</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/08.png" alt="Image">

<p>I mean, you’d think an Italian would know better than to defile pizza like that, but okay, I guess.</p>

<p>Then the opposition comes up with a frankly quite dumb idea of giving people in each case a choice of whether they wanted to allow UCC to apply to them. Any intelligent reader would be able to tell that that defeats the purpose of a uniform civil code.</p>

<p>Something to note is that Asaduddin Owaisi coughs very loudly in assembly, thereby
<ul>
    <li> breaking decorum and </li>
    <li> putting his fellow delegates (and more importantly, the press) in danger of falling ill.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p>He then proceeds to address the honourable Prime Minister as ‘shrimati’ instead of ‘shriman’, a blatant act of disrespect for the representative of the nation. Then he accidentally provides a ringing endorsement of Modiji by  pointing out that Benares has a 30% Muslim population, and yet Modiji one. This can only mean that Our Dear Leader is loved by all – regardless of what seditious elements may say.</p>

<p>Farooq Abdullah brings up the Special Marriage Act of 1954 in the context of inter-faith marriages, but what he perhaps doesn’t know is that there are a lot of flaws with the act, such as any person being allowed to object to the marriage upto THIRTY DAYS from the marriage being filed.</p>
<p>There was another embarrassing moment for the opposition as Arvind Kejriwal continued his hapless day where he went against everything he’s said in the past, by appearing to question Asaduddin Owaisi, even though he’s not, you know, supposed to be doing that. <p>
</p>There was another right to reply instance where the Hyderabad MP used allegations which had been dropped against Tejaswi Surya, to question his integrity. Tejaswi lost, and was silenced for 15 minutes.<p>
</p>Meanwhile, Kejriwal manages to group reservation in with corruption and police brutality as issues to be fixed. Honestly just a bad day all around for him. <p>
</p>Modi and P- Rahul Gandhi have a debate where RaGa suggests that Modi focus on fixing the legal system first before he implements UCC. Modi thanks him for his  ingenious solution of fixing the legal system, but he believes that that is not in the list of things he is supposed to do, so no, he will focus on UCC instead. <p>
</p>Then we reached the most entertaining part of the day as Ramesh Pokhriyal and Mamata Bannerjee kept making barbs at each other’s positions and the speaker was hapless until both were gagged. <p>
</p>However, Pokhriyal did manage to make some points. He introduced educational reforms – abolishing madrassas would prevent brainwashing and provide knowledge that could actually be used. In his opinion, shutting down madrassas would be more important than shutting down gurukuls. He also claimed(rightly) that Ramayan and Mahabharat teach us about the history of India. He made a parliamentary enquiry for a mic to drop, was denied, and promptly left. As will I. BYE<p>

<p>PS: I managed to snag a short interview with Rahul Gandhi. Here’s how it went:
<ul>
<li>He said he was strongly opposed to the UCC, but hadn’t spoken out until now because he felt that the word of other senior Congress leaders would have been enough</li>
<li>He believed me when I said Priyanka Gandhi(his sister) had spoken out against UCC (she hadn’</li>
<li>He is of the opinion that the BJP is creating a “politics of polarisation” which will be a “central challenge” in India</li>
<li>He seemed unable to adequately explain his remarks of “I am a Hindu… India belongs to the Hindus”</li>
</ul>
</p>]]></content><author><name>Zee</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first day began with a General Speakers’ List (GSL) with 20 speakers, lasting 30 minutes. The topic of discussion was the Uniform Civil Code(UCC). The first couple of hours consisted of banal back-and-forth between the opposition and the government, with all representatives making the same points – the opposition stating, “you can’t impose your rules on other communities,” and the government enlightening them: “ Many of the personal laws are prejudiced against women in general. Hence, we must have a uniform code to ensure parity for all.”]]></summary></entry></feed>