<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-15T14:39:12+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LokSabha22</title><subtitle>A Blog by DebSoc</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Modi Sides with Nupur Sharma: Unprecedented or Expected?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/modi-nupur.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modi Sides with Nupur Sharma: Unprecedented or Expected?" /><published>2022-06-14T22:00:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T22:00:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/modi-nupur</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/modi-nupur.html"><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking turn of events, the prime minister Narendra Modi revealed that he agreed with Nupur Sharma about the controversial statements she made about the Muslim prophet Mohammed. Last week, she came under fire for making offensive comments that angered Muslims and incited communal violence across the country. That resulted in the BJP removing her as their spokesperson, which was only done “because they had to”, according to his press conference today. Nupur Sharma stated that she was driven to retaliate because the other person had insulted her religion. Is the BJP not aware of the limitations of freedom of speech? Or are they convinced of their invincibility just because they’ve won the elections the past two times?</p>

<p>When confronted with questions about his past statements, Nitin Gadkari, the Minister for Road Transport and Highways, seemed to feign innocence repeatedly. He was spotted shouting “Jai Shri Ram,” a known Hindutva slogan, multiple times in assembly. He did not seem to remember controversial comments he made about the Navy, and when questioned about the corruption charges against him, after a long period of discrediting genuine sources, he declined to comment. Even the leader of his own party, the prime minister, refused to say anything about the proven charges. </p>

<p>Why does the BJP choose to repeatedly side with dishonorable ministers and even go as far as to defend them? The hasty implementation of the UCC across 4 states discredits them even further. Even after Nupur Sharma accepted that her removal from the party was fair, her party leaders kept defending her and her “opinion”. Is ignoring blatant islamophobia going to be the agenda of the BJP going forward? Is this a display of incompetency, or are these their actual beliefs (which would prove to be far worse for the people of this nation)? Why does the BJP continue to make exceptions for ministers whose actions go against the very spirit of democracy? Especially when it comes to something like the UCC, which they are expected to reach an agreement on tomorrow, can they really afford lapses in judgment like these. The author is concerned about the implications of this and what they mean for the people of this nation.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Wire</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a shocking turn of events, the prime minister Narendra Modi revealed that he agreed with Nupur Sharma about the controversial statements she made about the Muslim prophet Mohammed. Last week, she came under fire for making offensive comments that angered Muslims and incited communal violence across the country. That resulted in the BJP removing her as their spokesperson, which was only done “because they had to”, according to his press conference today. Nupur Sharma stated that she was driven to retaliate because the other person had insulted her religion. Is the BJP not aware of the limitations of freedom of speech? Or are they convinced of their invincibility just because they’ve won the elections the past two times?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exclusive Hint at Badruddin Ajmal’s Lok Sabha Bill</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exclusive Hint at Badruddin Ajmal’s Lok Sabha Bill" /><published>2022-06-14T21:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T21:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ajmal.html"><![CDATA[<p>Badruddin Ajmal provided The Hindu with an exclusive peek at the bill he proposes to publish in the Lok Sabha -</p>

The scheme we need to follow to solve the pertinent question:

<ol>
    <li>Draft a UCC.</li>
    <li>Decide cases of personal law in the following manner:
        <ol>
            <li>Ask each of the parties what law system they would like to follow</li>
            <li>If there is a unanimous consensus on a particular law system, use it. If not, use the UCC.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
</ol>

This system will preserve the freedom of religion as well as uphold the
fundamental rights of everyone, including women and minorities.

Example illustrating point ii)

Suppose there is a personal law case pertaining to marriage. Then each of the
parties in the case must choose between

<ol>
    <li> The Hindu Marriage Act, 1955 </li>
    <li> The Indian Christian Marriage Act, 1872 </li>
    <li> The Parsi Marriage and Divorce Act of 1936 </li>
    <li> Muslim Marriage Act </li>
    <li> Any other religious laws </li>
    <li> The Uniform Civil Code, 2022 </li>
</ol>

<p>If ALL the parties are in agreement on one of these options, then the agreed upon law should be the law used to decide the case.</p>

<p>Else The Uniform Civil Code, 2022 shall be used.</p>

<p>The MP proposes drafting a UCC, then debating over each and every law in personal laws with representation from all political parties, and if a unanimous decision is not achieved, a suitable clause from the UCC draft shall be implemented across India.</p>

<p>However, the proposed bill neither specifies the contents of the UCC, nor does it hint upon the members that will be a part of the drafting committee.</p>

<p>Moreover, the cause of accommodating each and every minority in India, including women, hasn’t been discussed in the draft we received.</p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Badruddin Ajmal provided The Hindu with an exclusive peek at the bill he proposes to publish in the Lok Sabha -]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Collective Amnesia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/amnesia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collective Amnesia" /><published>2022-06-14T21:00:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T21:00:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/amnesia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/amnesia.html"><![CDATA[<p>Zee News had the exclusive opportunity to interview Kerala CM Pinarayi Vijayan anHyderabad MP and AIMIM leader Asaduddin Owaisi. </p>

<p>First up was Mr. Vijayan, who seemed as if he wanted the interview to end as soon as possible, and kept making to leave, but was asked to stay by our reporter. </p>

<p>To start with, he was asked about his recurrent assertions that “Kerala is not a communal state… It has no history of communal violence.” He confirmed that he had indeed said that. Our reporter then showed him what a quick Google search would disclose – the Marad massacres (2002 and 2003, 78 CPI(M) members were among those arrested for their involvement), the Thalassery riots (1961; saw 569 violent incidents, 63 mosques and 3 temples were attacked; At the time, he was a CPI-M MLA from the nearby Koothuparamba constituency, and area secretary in Thalassery before that), and the 2009 Valiyathura riots while the LDF government headed by him was in power. He seemed to be at a loss to explain his statements in light of these revelations. Our reporter was reminded of these words </p>

<pre>                   
                    औरो के ख्यालात की लेते हैं तलाशी 
                    और अपने गरेबान में झाँका नहीं जाता
</pre>

<p>Something which was very shocking was his inability to remember the names of the constituencies that he served in. For instance, he said he was an MLA for Panoor when asked to confirm by our reporter, even though he never has been. When pressed, he became defensive and started deflecting the questions, asking our reporter if he remembered every single article he had written, which is a completely different ball game and irrelevant to the matter at hand.</p>

<p>Constituencies are very different from articles, and despite our best efforts we fail to wrap our head around the honestly nonsensical analogy.</p>

<p>He also attempted to wipe himself of blame by claiming that he was an old man, that he is 77 years old and can’t remember things these days. This begs the exceedingly alarming question of why then, does he believe he is the right person to not only vote in the House of the People on matters of national importance but also fit to be the chief minister of an entire state and call the shots when he himself proclaims that he cannot remember basic minutiae. Experience only goes so far. What is more essential is having a mental faculty capable of working at the highest level.</p>

<p>Another factually incorrect statement that he made was when asked what his party had done since saying “What is urgently required is reform in various personal laws. This is an exercise that brooks no delay”  back in 2003. After all, if it ‘brook[ed] no delay’, some steps should have been taken in that direction, especially given his party had been in power for all terms since but one. However, the only response the CPI(M) leader could muster was that Sitaram Yechury had brought it up in the Lower House. Moreover, he said that the UCC was a central issue (which is irrelevant, albeit true) and so the state government could not do anything about it. </p>

<p>This is objectively untrue because personal laws are an item in the Concurrent List, which means that both Central and State Governments have the power to legislate on it. Hence, the LDF could have introduced reforms if it so wished. One wonders why they did not, especially given their insistence that they are urgently needed. Something to ponder upon.</p>

<p>Talking about more recent affairs, with Opposition parties in Kerala holding protests to seek his resignation, the Chief Minister has been under fire ever since the accused in the case, Swapna Suresh, alleged he took currency out of the country with the help of a diplomat from the UAE Consulate in Thiruvananthapuram in 2016. He did not provide any substantial answers.</p>

<p>AIMIM chief Owaisi was asked about his statements in the House about him not already being in the UCC special committee despite “being a leader of the All India Muslim Personal Law Board,” an organization which has previously been described as a “purely religious organization… not a political one” by both the AIMPLB  and Owaisi himself . In that case, how does it make sense to involve their leader in the special committee, which requires political knowledge in addition to religious expertise. More damning, however, is the fact that he is not a leader of the AIMPLB. There is zero mention of him in the list of AIMPLB leaders. When this was pointed out to him, he flat-out denied it even though he had confirmed that he said it mere seconds ago. At that point there is nothing one can do if a representative of the people is dishonest in his answers. </p>

<p>There is one last thing we would like to say to those who seek to hide the truth</p>

<pre>
                  हमसे उम्मीद मत रखना की हम कुछ और लिखेंगे,
                        हम Zee News हैं साहब, 
                    जब भी लिखेंगे बेखौफ होकर लिखेंगे..!!
</pre>]]></content><author><name>Zee News</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zee News had the exclusive opportunity to interview Kerala CM Pinarayi Vijayan anHyderabad MP and AIMIM leader Asaduddin Owaisi.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drama in Moderated Caucus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drama in Moderated Caucus" /><published>2022-06-14T20:00:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T20:00:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/caucus.html"><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi commenced the speeches with the government’s plan to implement UCC with an introduction to the committee structure, which will have a proportional representation from Lok Sabha MPs and equal representation from all minorities and women rights advocates. UCC will first be implemented in BJP ruled states such as Uttar Pradesh, and will be enforced all over India in three years. Upon being asked about the proportion of Lok Sabha members in the committee by Vijayan, Modi promptly replied that he didn’t need to clarify and that the plan should be looked up.<p>

<p>Nupur Sharma said that the proportional representation will be that of political parties and contradicted the PM by saying that the “experiment” in specific states will last for three years. She also said that implementing in some states first will prevent uprising.<p>

<p>Vijayan pointed out that the NDA just recently started talking about the implementation of UCC, and that it was ironic that the same people who want UCC don’t have a single clue about how to implement it. He elaborated that the CPI(M) initially supported UCC but no longer does as the predominant supporter of the same, i.e. BJP is involved in the oppression of minorities. He suggested changing the personal laws instead which would achieve the same goals as the UCC as explained by the BJP. Nupur Sharma replied that the agenda of implementing UCC was to bring everyone under a common law, and Modi said that implementing UCC in BJP ruled states will be successful as time would be spent actually seeing the effects of the law rather than bickering with state governments such as that of Mamata Banerjee.<p>

<p>Uddhav Thakeray pressed that UCC was required for national unity, and that it will remove the pressure and influence of foreign entities on personal law boards. Gogoi continues by bashing BJP by saying that implementing in BJP ruled states won’t prevent riots by pointing towards the clashes and protests caused by Nupur Sharma’s remarks last week. Gogoi bashed BJP by announcing that the anti-Muslim and that the only reason that they were against polygamous marriage was that it was allows allowed to Sharia law. He said that BJP is in the business of passing bills without consulting any of the relevant stakeholders first. Modi replied that he doesn’t care about any religious scriptures; all that matters is that everyone enjoys basic human rights. It must be noted that Irani said that personal laws resembled the divide and conquer method used by the British.<p>

<p>“Women’s rights are subjective, “said Farooq Abdullah. He mentioned that human rights are subject to cultural interpretation, and that Kashmiris still protest against the removal of article 370. Tharoor added that the government plans on sitting and watching as the introduction of UCC in select states will lead to the same turmoil the nation experienced during the 2002 Gujarat riots. Shashi Tharoor continued by saying that the government cannot be trusted to uphold the dignity and culture of minorities as BJP ruled states have passed laws against religious conversion, which was responded to by stating that the laws were anti-forceful conversion.<p>

<p>Manohar Lal Khattar passes an inflammatory comment when he said that some personal laws didn’t respect females, and refused to list down the referred personal laws. He also announced that the entire parliament will get to decide on members of the UCC committee.<p>

<p>MK Stalin was certainly not taking the matter seriously as he was laughing and swaying while giving his speech. He said that the DMK will support UCC as long as it’s implemented in the same way as Ajmal intended. He added that India should “de-moss” and copy UK’s or USSR’s UCC implementations as the BJP wasn’t capable.<p>

<p>Naqvi reprimanded the opposition for repeatedly taking things out of context. He mentioned that intellect isn’t affected by religion, and that changing personal laws didn’t achieve the same thing as UCC as law making isn’t about accommodating some people more and some less; everyone must be equal. Rahul Gandhi passed a sarcastic remark by saying that “Religious communities will definitely be respectful of other religions.”. In his reply, Naqvi reminded the opposition that protests don’t mean that the action was wrong - it can also mean that some people misinterpreted the action.<p>

<p>Swami expressed his opinion that Stalin was very concerned about the contents of the UCC, and Kejriwal said that BJP was interested in meddling with personal laws. BJP replied to the CM by saying that the aspiration for UCC is present under Article 44 of the constitution, and that changes such as implementing the Hindu Succession law wasn’t taken well by people initially but its results are evident. Kejriwal further added that the government cited article 44 a lot, but didn’t pay heed to Article 35 which said that UCC should only be implemented when there was a general agreement across the nation. The opposition pressed that BJP engages in polarizing Indians which was clearly evident with BJP’s share in Hindu votes rising exponentially through the years.<p>

<p>The moderated caucus that had begun the previous session ended at 4PM. It was observed that the speaker was biased in not letting certain vocal MPs reply to the other blocks.<p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi commenced the speeches with the government’s plan to implement UCC with an introduction to the committee structure, which will have a proportional representation from Lok Sabha MPs and equal representation from all minorities and women rights advocates. UCC will first be implemented in BJP ruled states such as Uttar Pradesh, and will be enforced all over India in three years. Upon being asked about the proportion of Lok Sabha members in the committee by Vijayan, Modi promptly replied that he didn’t need to clarify and that the plan should be looked up.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The opposition says some things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The opposition says some things" /><published>2022-06-14T19:19:19+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T19:19:19+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/same-things.html"><![CDATA[<p>The second day of the Lok Sabha picks up from where the first one ended. Some more barbs regarding implementation of UCC are traded, and a point of contention is about the initial implementation of UCC being in Gujarat and Uttar Pradesh, communally diverse states which are governed by the BJP. The opposition questions why a phased rollout, and why in states governed by the BJP. The central government’s response points out that a phased rollout helps to observe how well it works, and the practical difficulties faced can be fixed in the subsequently chosen states. The reason for choosing those states is that the central government would prefer working with co-operative state governments, and not those who would seek to complain and create hurdles at every turn and delay the process at every turn, an example being the TMC government in West Bengal.<p>

<p>Another ‘problem’ brought up was that Uttar Pradesh had the lowest Human Development Index (HDI) in India, which is objectively untrue and was fact-checked by UP CM Yogi Adityanath. Modiji closed by asking the pertinent question of where his concerns ought to lie, in the safety and happiness of women or in what Sharia law or the Holy Bible say?<p>

<p>The assembly then broke for an unmoderated caucus. Amazingly, AIUDF chief Badruddin Ajmal, who is regularly listed among <a href="https://themuslim500.com/profiles/badruddin-ajmal-qasmi/">"The 500 Most Influential Muslims" of the world</a>, was heard saying ‘India is not a nice country, there are much nicer countries,’ with Hyderabad MP Asaduddin Owaisi repeatedly asking him to ‘shut up, the press is right here.’<p>

<p>After the unmoderated caucus, there were some crisis updates, which caused quite a stir. Foremost among them was the fact that RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat had stated that he was excited to join the special committee of the UCC. The opposition made quite a meal of this statement even after it was clarified that he was simply one of those considered for it, and that there would be equal representation for all.<p>

<p>Mamata Bannerjee and Arvind Kejriwal threatened to go to the Supreme Court even though the matter was still under discussion in the House. Kejriwal also made the distractionary demand of statehood for Delhi. The BJP revealed that it had modified its original plan to now implement UCC first in West Bengal, Kerala, Kashmir, and Uttar Pradesh after consultation with the opposition, indicating that they are and have been open to constructive criticism.<p>

<p>One of the most controversial speeches of the day came towards the end and was made by TMC MP Mahua Moitra, who asked, “Do you think Indians have the brains to follow  UCC laws? India is going to lawless and weak cowards… Indians don’t have listening skills and have a short attention span.” One wonders why the representative felt the need to be so provocative in her speech, and what she intended to achieve.<p>

<p>The day closed with an open press conference. Turn to Page 2 for  our coverage.<p>]]></content><author><name>Zee News</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second day of the Lok Sabha picks up from where the first one ended. Some more barbs regarding implementation of UCC are traded, and a point of contention is about the initial implementation of UCC being in Gujarat and Uttar Pradesh, communally diverse states which are governed by the BJP. The opposition questions why a phased rollout, and why in states governed by the BJP. The central government’s response points out that a phased rollout helps to observe how well it works, and the practical difficulties faced can be fixed in the subsequently chosen states. The reason for choosing those states is that the central government would prefer working with co-operative state governments, and not those who would seek to complain and create hurdles at every turn and delay the process at every turn, an example being the TMC government in West Bengal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BJP marches on with UCC plans, Modi supports Nupur Sharma, other party members outraged</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BJP marches on with UCC plans, Modi supports Nupur Sharma, other party members outraged" /><published>2022-06-14T17:40:28+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T17:40:28+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/toi-ucc.html"><![CDATA[<p>In stark contrast to yesterday today’s session saw a plethora of developments during the committee’s discussion on UCC.<p>

<p>Two prominent CMs, Jagan Reddy of Telangana and MK Stalin of Tamil Nadu finally showed up to the committee, wanting to make an impact on the proceedings (spoiler alert – they didn’t)<p>

<p>The session began with the committee continuing the discussion which took place yesterday: on the implementation of the UCC. However, unlike yesterday, the pro-UCC bloc actually had a proper plan this time. The Prime Minister and other pro-UCC bloc members talked about creating a committee with proportionate representation from the Lok Sabha, and equal representation from all religions and minorities on top of that. The BJP would not comment, however, on the proportions of the representation.<p>

<p>A 3-year trial period was also planned for implementation of UCC in BJP-ruled states, after which it would be implemented in other states (based on the success of the trial period). <p>

<p>The anti-UCC bloc pointed out that the proposed committee representation would still end up being biased towards Hindus, with Akhilesh Yadav in particular calling out how “minorities will be under-represented”. The decision of only trialling the system in BJP-ruled states was also heavily criticized.<p>

<p>It seemed that MK Stalin was blissfully unaware of the magnitude of the issue at hand, as he was seen giggling and laughing for little reason throughout the session. Even during his speech, he chose to be in support of the UCC if “Badruddin Ajmal’s interpretation is followed”. Remember, this was the leader who previously claimed that UCC was “an attempt to divert attention by the Union government”. When called out on this deviation by the other MPs, his only defence was that his party was a “flexible party which wants to listen to the needs of the people”. Though, it seems unclear why Stalin is suddenly pandering to Hindus.<p>

<p>Some MPs such as Abbas Naqvi were still innocent enough to believe in ideal-world scenarios. He claimed that “respected individuals from one community will not cause harm to other communities”, and that “intellect doe not have a religion”. When issues of instigated communal riots were brought up, Naqvi was unable to provide a response, apart from an attempt at deflecting the blame back at Rahul by noting how there were riots in his constituency as well. It was unclear how this was related to Rahul’s question and how Naqvi thought it would strengthen his point.<p>

<p>Farooq Abdullah’s history of eye-raising comments continued as he called women’s rights a “subjective matter”. When pressed on this point, he claimed that BJP “does not have the right to decide what women’s rights are”.<p>

<p>The committee then broke for a small informal session where both blocs tried to strengthen their battle plan. But while this was happening, it was observed that Badruddin Ajmal was going around to every person with “something” in his hand and asking for their opinion and support on the matter. Upon a minor investigation, it was revealed that Ajmal had already created a bill toward the implementation of the UCC, and was trying to get support for it. He would eventually announce it in public later on, and sure enough, he also ended up changing blocs after the break.<p>

<p>However, that wasn’t remotely the biggest development during the break. BJP were so confident in their numeric advantage, that they released a statement noting their confidence on UCC being implemented in the next 3 years. The proposed committee would consist of people whom the Lok Sabha deemed “relevant stakeholders”. BJP also drastically altered the pilot states for the trial, choosing to test the UCC in Kerala, West Bengal, Kashmir and Uttar Pradesh. And as if that was not enough, the RSS President publicly expressed his “excitement” to join the UCC draft committee.<p>

<p>Needless to say, the anti-UCC bloc was completely outraged. Their view was that the states selected were not “random”, and was a deliberate ploy to suppress the people in these states. Kerala’s CM Pinarayi Vijayan strongly believed that if anything went wrong during the process, his people would be labelled anti-nationalists. Multiple members insinuated that the BJP would even declare an Emergency.<p>

<p>BJP’s response? They were merely doing what the house told them to do – make the list of trial states as diverse as possible. PM Modi retorted by pointing out the hypocrisy of the complaining anti-UCC bloc by noting that “these were the same people who complained when BJP-ruled states were picked”. But they were unable to provide other suitable responses for this decision.<p>

<p>The developments also resulted in multiple MPs “flexibly” changing their stance on the matter. MPs like Farooq Abdullah now were “begging” the BJP to trial the UCC only in BJP-ruled states, something which they had vehemently opposed prior to the recent developments. <p>

<p>Another issue of major contention was the supposed inclusion of the RSS President in the UCC draft committee. Many members of the house brought up his colourful history – Owaisi mentioned him “calling for open murder of Muslims” – and were incensed that a right-wing Hindu nationalist was given a spot in committee. Owaisi wondered if the RSS President got a spot in the committee, why did he – a member of AIMPLB – not get a spot on the committee yet?<p>

<p>The BJP MPs seemed to provide different responses for these questions. Nirmala Sitharaman was of the opinion that the RSS president has the sympathy of a lot of Hindu people in the country, making him a relevant stakeholder – basically confirming his inclusion into the committee. But Nupur Sharma and Narendra Modi said otherwise, arguing that the RSS President was only under consideration and was talked to regarding the committee. They attempted to deflect the issue by mentioning that they had no control over what the RSS President says in public. It was clear that there were some cracks in the BJP’s story.<p>

<p>Later on, a press conference took place where the MPs were grilled by reporters from the various press bodies. Throughout the course of this conference, multiple leaders suffered from “severe amnesia”, and those who didn’t, made several accusations of “fake news”.<p>

<p>It was during this press conference when PM Modi dropped the biggest bombshell of the night – he openly voiced his support for Nupur Sharma. His view was that her comments were a result of her freedom of speech, which should be respected. Wonder how he would have reacted if the deity being defamed was a Hindu one: would he still be rambling about “freedom of speech”?<p>]]></content><author><name>Times of India</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In stark contrast to yesterday today’s session saw a plethora of developments during the committee’s discussion on UCC.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BJP says UCC to be implemented in states of Kerala, West Bengal. Is it just a coincidence?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BJP says UCC to be implemented in states of Kerala, West Bengal. Is it just a coincidence?" /><published>2022-06-14T16:00:44+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T16:00:44+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/ucc-kerala.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session today started with the the parliament trying to find  proper implementation methods of UCC to which senior BJP ministers like Mr. modi and Ms Nupur Sharma suggested to make a prototype of the UCC rules by making a committee having “proportionate” representation political party members and religious members , this “ proportionate “ was questioned by the congress leader and raised many speculation of how the BJP is trying to ‘HINDUFY’ the country.<p>

<p>BJP leaders also suggested the implementation should be trial for 3 years in the states of kerala ,west bengal .This suggestion faced strong backlash from the opposition leaders .Mr. Owaisi rightly opposed it with the argument  that BJP’s selection of states is not “random” owaisi points out how they have selected the states not ruled by BJP so that riots which follow (which are inevitable ) will be blamed on the state , on this note PM modi even commented that if the riots are violent they won't hesitate to put an emergency which essentially puts the center in charge<p>

<p>Press conference followed in the later part of the day where NDTV reporters had the chance to interview the all talented and sensible BJP minister Mr. Tejaswi Surya . when asked about how can the people of the nation trust him and the BJP while making the rules for UCC after openly giving  the remarks about how muslim religioun is so impractical and making fun of many sharia laws , he stubornly replied to this question that since the people have voted him they have to trust him even if he gives nasty remarks on muslim laws.<p>

<p>And when asked about his views on an incident in uttar pradesh he replied with i don't care about uttar pradesh ,i am from bangalore , as if the UCC (if implemented )will be implemented only in his constituencies and not in the entire nation.<p>

<p>In the press conference the prime minister of the nation Mr. Narendra Damodar Modi  didn’t had answers to most questions asked by the press (maybe he is out of practice in attending press conferences ) but he was very confident in speaking in support of Ms Nupur “controversy” Sharma about the nasty remarks she gave on prophet mohammed , He defended Ms Sharma calling her remarks as freedom of speech (offensive speech never existed ) . Modi ji did this after Nupur Sharma had openly accepted that her suspension from the party was correct .<p>

<p>This shows how the BJP represents itself as a secular party and then like a snake shed its skin and show its true color.<p>

<p>Now the question is Will the parliament come to a conclusion on the final day , will the all efficient speakers of the BJP be able to brainwash the parliament with their supposedly “right” ideas or will the UCC remain a myth as it always has been …<p>]]></content><author><name>NDTV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session today started with the the parliament trying to find proper implementation methods of UCC to which senior BJP ministers like Mr. modi and Ms Nupur Sharma suggested to make a prototype of the UCC rules by making a committee having “proportionate” representation political party members and religious members , this “ proportionate “ was questioned by the congress leader and raised many speculation of how the BJP is trying to ‘HINDUFY’ the country.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jyotiraditya Scindi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jyotiraditya Scindi" /><published>2022-06-14T15:45:13+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T15:45:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/14/scindia.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia, the Congress member who switched BJP in 2020, was interviewed by The Hindu in the first session of the Parliament today.</p>

<p><i>The interview commenced only after the Rajya Sabha MP glanced through the web to check whether The Hindu’s political alliance lied with the NDA.</i> <b>The Hindu would like to press that we don’t affiliate ourselves with any political entity, Indian or otherwise, and are completely unbiased in our views.</b><p>

<p>In your experience, out of BJP and Congress, which party do you think respects the secular nature of the country?<p>

<p>Scindia replied that he thought BJP was more accommodating of minorities’ opinions. He didn’t comment on the revolts in response to CAA, and other such NDA implemented laws.<p>

<p>Are you aware of some other countries that have implemented UCC? The MP replied that he did. Are you aware of the fact that Saudi Arabia has a uniform civil code? The MP wasn’t. <p>

<p>Countries such as Saudi Arabia, Turkey, Pakistan and so on, have a uniform code for everyone, but in contrast to the aspirations of the Indian constitution, it has been implemented according to Sharia law.<p>

<p>With reference to the last question, how can the nation trust BJP, a Hindutva party, to implement the UCC while considering the views of everyone? <p>

<p>The MP reiterated the government’s plans to have equal representation from all communities and proportional representation from the parliamentary members. Scindia added that the one of the main goals of UCC was to ensure equal rights for all women in the country and uphold the dignity of females. <p>

<p>What would you like to comment on Ramesh Pokhriyal saying that education in gurukuls produced the ideal Indians and education in madrasas brainwashed the youth?<p>

<p>The MP didn’t comment and provided the excuse of not being present in the parliament house when the inflammatory comment was made.<p>

<p>In your speech in the first session, you mentioned that India should follow the Belgium model. Could you elaborate on that?<p>

<p>Jyotiraditya Scindia mentioned the key characteristics of the Belgian problem - different language speaking majorities and special community governments that had the power to handle issues related, and address grievances, related to their own communities. <p>

<p>In Belgium, the communal governments have power over educational, cultural, and language related issues. Bar marriage related issues, isn’t this the same as personal laws in India? <p>

<p>The MP evaded the question and reiterated the point of a UCC. <p>

<p>In 2014, you mentioned that BJP polarizes the Indian community and damages the secular nature of our country. What has changed between then and 2022?<p>

<p>Scindia mentioned that opinions and facts change with time.<p>

<p>How do you feel about the fact that you rub shoulders with the same people who were present in the BJP when you made the previous comment?<p>

<p>The MP replied that opinions and people are allowed to change.<p>]]></content><author><name>The Hindu</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jyotiraditya Scindia, the Congress member who switched BJP in 2020, was interviewed by The Hindu in the first session of the Parliament today.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Owaisi Says, “UCC Takes Away Rights From Women”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Owaisi Says, “UCC Takes Away Rights From Women”" /><published>2022-06-12T22:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T22:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/owaise.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Lok Sabha Assembly’s first day marked a rather enthusiastic session. While it was an enthusiastic session with participation from most of the Members of the Parliament voicing their concerns regarding the Uniform Civil Code, it was apparent that the opposition was not able to provide convincing alternatives to UCC if not UCC, and continued vouching for the age-old discriminatory laws.</p>

<p>The session started with the Motion proposed by the Chief Minister of Uttar Pradesh, a UCC advocate, “framework and implementation of UCC”.</p>

<p>Towards the beginning of the session, Union Minister Mukhtar Abbas Naqvi backed up his previous statements by portraying strong approval towards implementing the Uniform Civil Code for all the citizens of India. He said, “India is a nation of peace and acceptance. people are arrogant to assume personal laws are superior.” He claimed that the “heavenly laws” made about 2000 years ago were discriminatory towards women and the less fortunate people of the society and UCC would ensure they are given rights.</p>

<p>On a rather interesting note, Asaduddin Owaisi explicitly said that the UCC would take away rights from women. He quoted that, “Hindu women have certain privileges that the UCC would in fact withdraw”. The panel of BJP MPs objected to this completely false statement. Owaisi seemed to have incorrectly learned and interpreted the UCC, as Anurag Thakur backed up, “UCC takes into consideration the current personal laws and does not take them away.“</p>

<p>Owaisi was further questioned by the right-leaning MPs when he mentioned, “Polygamy among Hindus was in fact more than the polygamy found in Muslims”. This statement not only baffled the panel of members of the parliament, but left the audience, press, and the speaker perplexed. Upon being questioned about his sources, he mentioned and we quote “1954 census reported this.” These laughable comments were visibly cross-examined by the audience as it left them confused.</p>

<p>MP Manoj Tiwari, remarkably convinced his point that the opposition has based their entire problems on the implementations of UCC and has not rather given a thought about the overall picture and how beneficial it could be. He conveyed his message by using quite an interesting “pizza” analogy. He reinstated that we are all Indian citizens above all and that existence of personal identity will not be harmed, which the opposition seemed to have forgotten.</p>

<p>Admittedly going against his own party’s stated position Tharoor, in fact, backed the idea proposed by BJP. He said, “this law has the capability of giving women and the people of the LGBTQ community rights.” He also received support and applause from the ruling party for stating, “One nation, One Law”.</p>

<p>During the second motion, “If not UCC, then what?” proposed by Scindia, it became apparent that the opposition had no clear idea about what they had in mind if not UCC. According to spokesperson Manoj Tiwari, “opposition’s policy is completely redundant and they should just go along with UCC. Implementation of UCC is also a matter of debate. Stating and wording UCC in a different way is not suggesting an alternative.”</p>

<p>Today’s session, although was only the first of the many to come, made the picture very clear. The ruling party had a sharp vision of the UCC and its framework, however, the opposition, confused, could not give good enough alternatives to UCC, nor could completely criticise UCC.</p>]]></content><author><name>Republic TV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Lok Sabha Assembly’s first day marked a rather enthusiastic session. While it was an enthusiastic session with participation from most of the Members of the Parliament voicing their concerns regarding the Uniform Civil Code, it was apparent that the opposition was not able to provide convincing alternatives to UCC if not UCC, and continued vouching for the age-old discriminatory laws.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCC Should be Implemented, Says BJP Ministers, and They Won’t be Biased and Take Care of all Religions but Will They?" /><published>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T21:04:14+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/NDTV-UCC-implemented.html"><![CDATA[<p>The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .</p>

<p>The recently suspended spokesperson Nupur Sharma also talked about how everyone should be under one umbrella but faced strong backlash from the opposition leaders like VIJAYAN that nupur sharma herself gave a very controversial remark on prophet which is being acknowledged all over the world and Mr. Vijayan also talks about how BJP keeps naming the cities according to a “particular” religion and how there are many cases of religion bias in BJP ruling states . He supposedly concreted his claim in front of the executive board that the Uniform civil code made by the ruling party won't be that uniform ….</p>

<p>But in totally contrast to the above claims by the BJP ministers about the UCC being not biased MR. tejaswi Surya who was punished for 15 min silence in the lok sabha where he was downvoted by his own party members on a point to reply , he openly stated that how the muslims laws were totally impractical and claimed the superiority of hindu laws , he even said “Teen-Teen shadiyan karne se pehle kuch kaam kar lete hai ” while addressing Mr Owasii.</p>

<p>In the moderated caucus on the topic “if not UCC then what ”</p>

<p>Mr. nitin gadkari says that their parties main focus will be on eradicating “unfair or evil “ practices from the religious laws but was rightly opposed by shree Rahul Gandhi that the norms of “evil” are being judged by BJP. He gives example of beef ban in BJP led UTTAR PRADESH where beef was evil according to a “particular” religion so the claims of evil and not evil are totally controversial.</p>

<p>On an interesting note Mr. Jamyang Namgyal was captured sleeping in the parliament during his "own" Prime minister Narendra Modi's speech.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/img/posts/07.jpeg" alt="Image">]]></content><author><name>NDTV</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The session of lok sabha started with general speakers speech where members of the bharatiya janata party like Anurag Thakur stated that the if UCC is made, it will comprehend the religious beliefs of all the religion , the newly made aviation minister jyotiraditya scindia who recently switched party from congress to BJP spoke on how the UCC won't be dominated by “any” religion .]]></summary></entry></feed>